MING-HSU LEE

E-mail: mattlee588@hotmail.com

An experienced regional manager in IT/CE industry. Strong in people management, communication and business development. Highly successful in building relationships with upper-level decision makers, seizing control of critical problem areas, and delivering on customer commitments.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Abilities to create strategies of sales/marketing and client proposals
- Management ability for putting different groups together as a team to achieve goals
- Management ability for business start-up and product development
- Language ability (English/Japanese/Mandarin/Taiwanese)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2014 - Present GN Netcom (Japan) Ltd.

Country Manager, Consumer Solutions Japan

Jan. 2014 - Present

- Providing leadership and management to Jabra consumer business in Japan.
- Fully responsible for managing and driving all commercial activities, channel expansion, customer care and P&L optimization.
- Work closely with customer services, marketing and finance departments to improve the operational excellence.
- Act as point of escalation towards global/regional organization (Supply Chain/ After-Market Services/ Product Management...).

Key Achievements:

Reshaped the team to meet objectives, achieved over 40% year-on-year growth in 2014 for Jabra branded products.

2013 - 2014 SanDisk Limited

Sr. Strategic Account Manager, Commercial Sales and Support

May 2013 - Jan. 2014

- Responsible for building commercial channel model in Japan.
- Responsible for revenue generation through commercial channel sales of SanDisk SSDs and other storage devices.

Key Achievements:

- Worked with internal stakeholders (Finance, Sales Operation, FAE...) to build a team for supporting commercial business channel in Japan successfully.
- Identified and signed up the 1st distributor in 3 months.
- Working on marketing plan and channel partner program with marketing team for distributors to drive business in Japan.

2001 - 2013 Logicool Co., Ltd., Tokyo, Japan

Sr. Manager, Strategic Accounts, B2B Regional & OEM Sales Country Manager, OEM Sales, Asia Pacific & Japan Apr. 2012 - Apr. 2013

Oct. 2008 - Mar. 2012

- Led a sales team to generate revenue and drive business growth in Asia Pacific and Japan.
- Created sales strategies and business plan for APJ sales team to achieve company's goals.
- Coached team members to execute business strategies efficiently.
- Managed client communications and relationships with strategic accounts.

Key Achievements:

- Succeed in managing fewer team members to maintain consistent revenue and keep driving revenue growth after the Great Recession.
- Identified business models and created business plan within 6 months for the team to execute on selling individual products to corporate customers via strategic accounts.

Sales Manager, OEM Sales, Japan

Jul. 2001 - Oct. 2008

- Led all sales activities with key accounts and specific channel partners.
- Introduced new technology and product roadmap as solutions to customers timely for planning competitive products in the market.

Responsible for supporting customers to resolve issues during product development.

Kev Achievements:

- Won the 1st OEM webcam/headsets business with No. 1 PC manufacturer in Japan (2001).
- Won the 1st OEM optical mouse business with No. 1 PC manufacturer in Japan (2002).
- Won the 1st fully-customized wireless desktop (receiver/keyboard/mouse) business with No. 1 PC manufacturer in Japan (2004).
- Won the 1st fully-customized embedded camera module business with No. 2 PC manufacturer in Japan (2007).
- Succeed in selling USB headset/camera/gamepad/microphone to channel partners of console game software in Japan.

2000 – 2001 DELTA ELECTRONICS (JAPAN) INC., Tokyo, Japan

Sales Representative, 4th Sales Section, Sales Department

- Researched market capabilities of projectors, rear projection monitors and CD-R media in Japan.
- Developed new business opportunities in both OEM and Retail.

Key Achievements:

- Succeed in winning the 1st OEM projector business with Japanese electrical manufacturer.
- Established working relationship with new channel partner for selling CD-R media in retail market successfully.

1997 – 2000 Kolin-Denon Entertainment Inc., Taipei, Taiwan

A&R of International Repertoire, International Affairs Department

- Sourced for suitable Japanese music products for selling in Taiwan.
- Negotiated with licensors in Japan to make contracts on publishing licensed music CD in Taiwan.
- Created business plans for Sales team and promoters to execute.
- Managed music CD production, advertisement artwork design, and media plan.
- Edited product catalogue for channel partners.

Key Achievements:

- Planned and implemented business plan for all music albums of Noriko SAKAI during 2.5 years and gained a big success in sales in Taiwan and Hong-Kong.

1996 – 1997 Nippon Columbia Co., LTD., Tokyo, Japan

Engineer of Recording & Engineering Department

- Maintained recording equipment in recording studios.
- Developed modules of recording software.

EDUCATION

Master, Division of Audio and Visual Communication Studies

Kyushu Institute of Design, Fukuoka, Japan 1993 - 1996

Bachelor of Science, Department of Physics

Soochow University, Taipei, Taiwan 1988 - 1992

CERTIFICATION

.com Master★2001 ("NTT Communications Internet Certificate Examination")

REFERENCES

Will be upon request.